安心しろよ。 邪魔しに来たわけじゃないんだ。 むしろ　協力といっていい。 協力？ ああ。
As the fierce battle unfolded inside the palace, an immense number of citizens
hypnotized by Pouf's wing scales
もしも僕達が　クイズでトップになって カードを手に入れたら それを２５億円で 買い取ってもらいたい。
still waited outside for the selection process
that would turn them into soldier ants.
君らにしてみれば 成功報酬の５％だし 法外ってほどの額じゃないだろ？ あっ　そっか こいつら バッテラのこと知らないんだ
Meanwhile, a creature in the form that
they would soon become began to stir.
うわっ！　ハナっから分かんねえ ５択かよ！
Someone's watching me. And...
ナンバー１７ 「大天使の息吹」を入手するための 条件とは？
It's probably someone I know.
ナンバー０の カードのタイトルは？
No one's there?
やった！ １００種類コンプ！ フッ。 やったな！ 悔しいが完敗だ　おめでとう。
While her appearance hadn't totally changed, Palm was clearly no longer the same person.
ありがとう！ これで罰ゲームは　キルアだね。
And that greatly disturbed Killua.
クソ　俺　何点だったんだろ？
She was captured
「支配者からの招待」？
If Gon sees what's happened to Palm, he won't be able to take it...
同封のバッジを持つ者のみが 招待されるみたいだな。 リーメイロって城下町か…。
There's no room left in his heart.
１人で行かなきゃ ならないのかな？ 城の近くで　待っててやるよ。
If the transformation has
reached as far as Palm's heart...
グヘヘヘ…。
I can see Gon completely breaking down!
あのガキ マジで全部そろってるぜ。 よぉ　カードを全部賭けて 勝負しようぜ。
I must learn the answer.
悪いが　これは強制だ。
We still have a chance.
エッヘッヘッヘ。
Palm approached me herself!
フフフ…。
Palm?
エッヘッヘッヘ…。
Palm must have sensed me
えっ？
before I noticed her watching me...
それじゃあ 「アカンパニー」　１枚もらうね。
Using that power she told us about before.
あっ　それダメだ リーメイロ　まだ行ったことない。 それじゃあ 「ドリフト」でいいんじゃない？
Once I used my power, it was quite simple.
もう　他の街は全部行ったでしょ？ んじゃ　俺が「ドリフト」使って リーメイロに飛んだら
I thought she could use some kind
of divination to locate people.
迎えに戻って来る。
But it's probably closer to clairvoyance.
そしたら 「アカンパニー」が使えるね！ 「ドリフト」オン！
From her position, Palm shouldn't
have been able to see me...
おぉ　ビンゴ！
And if Palm were an enemy,
she would have backed off...
行くぜ　ゴン！ うん！
Clairvoyance is most effective from a distance.
「アカンパニー」オン！ リーメイロ！
And if she's an enemy, she shouldn't
remember me anymore.
すげぇ連中だな　あのべラム兄弟が あっという間だったぜ。
Since she approached me, she must remember me... Remember us!
確かに… 最初に会った時に比べて
Killua, yes?
あの少年２人は 格段に強くなった
I knew it...
だが　ゲンスルーと比較すると 力不足だったのは明らか
She has her memories!
策を練り うまくやったのだろうな
Where's Gon?
まぁ　いいさ ゲームの成功報酬は お前達にくれてやる
Once he's seen what I've
become, will Gon hate me?
「マグネティックフォース」オン！ クロロ＝ルシルフル！
Gon doesn't judge people by appearances.
除念で大もうけだ。
You're always so spiteful...
どんな気持かしらね。 「どんな」って？ だって　ジンに 会えるかもしれないんでしょ？
I have nothing to gain from your pity.
ずっと捜し求めてた父親に。
Where's Gon? Gon's with Pitou.
ようこそ グリードアイランド城へ。
Was it chance that you happened to find me?
どうぞ。
You're the one who turned the corner.
うっ！
Wrong! I sensed you watching me.
うわっ　汚っ！
That's why I came this way!
ん？　お 待ってた　待ってたぞ！ ジンの息子だってな　お前 こっち来て　座れ　座れ。
You noticed me first. Why are you lying?
えっと…　どこに座れば…。
Troublesome brat...
ん？　空いてってとこ　ねえか？
Where's Gon?
じゃあ　つくれ　つくれ こうやってよ。
Answer my question first. Did I notice Palm watching me
only when she physically saw me?
おっ！　あった　あった！ ん？
Does that mean Palm actually
saw me once, then immediately left?
ほらよ。 「支配者の祝福」 最高得点者への褒美だ。 どうだ　すげぇだろ！ 驚いた？　驚いた？
Then she used clairvoyance
to watch me follow her, and turned around so it'd look
like she was approaching me?
この街には　１万人の人間がいる。
For the last time...
その中に　もしかしたら…。 あ！　期待した？　期待した？
Where's Gon?
あれ　まさか　もっと安易に 支配者がジンだと思ってたとか？
I won't tell you.
思ってないよ ここにジンがいるなんて。 考えてもいないもん。
You're an enemy, aren't you?
１００種類のカード全てが そろったってわけだ
I made a mistake...
よって もう１つのイベントが発生する。
I used my power incorrectly.
えっと… お　あった　あった！ これだ　開けてみな。 そのバインダーには
When I was brimming with rage, I should have let my emotions take over!
ただし！　同じ番号のカードを 複数　入れることはできない。
Sh-She's dangerous!
あくまでも　お前のバインダーの 指定ポケットに入っている
Better to let everything out than hold it in.
１００枚の中から　３種　選ぶこと。 さて　これで　晴れて エンディングなわけだが
That includes my desire to kill you!
一般用なら 仲間と見られるでしょ？
Well? What now?
ほほ　なるほど　なるほど。 ドゥーンさん。 あっ？
Will you die without a word?
妙なイジワルは　やめてください。
Will you die after speaking?
僕達のこと… ご紹介が遅れました 僕はリスト　彼はドゥーン。 まっ　分かってると思うが お前の親父の連れだ。
Or will you just die?
君の父上が 最高責任者だったので 「Ｇ」から始まる単語を考えて 「グリード」でいいだろうと。
Palm's ability to arm herself by covering
her body with her hair, Black Widow, varied in appearance according
to her emotional state.
レイザーには会いました？ 彼が「Ｒ」で　僕が「Ｌ」です。
But defense was its primary function.
ゲームの最初に説明してた女性と 島外に出る小島にいた女性は双子。
What made Black Widow frightening
イータとエレナ どちらも頭文字は「Ｅ」。 で　次は「Ｄ」なんだが… 聞きてぇか？　聞きてぇだろ？
was the fact that she could rely on
her hair armor for protection, allowing her to devote all
her energy to her attacks.
ホントに　ひでぇ奴だぞ！ ひでぇ奴！ く！
P-Palm-san! Turn off your Hatsu!
俺の名前はドゥーンだ 頭文字は何だと思う？
Palm is an Enhancer.
えっ？　「Ｄ」でしょ？ く　お前まで　そう言うか？
When everything clicks, it's possible
to become this much stronger?
やっぱ　そうだよな ジンの息子だもんな！
I completely blocked the attack,
but I still took damage.
だって　次は「Ｄ」って…。 「Ｗ」だよ　「Ｗ」！
If the fight drags on, I'll be at a total disadvantage. But I can't run away.
ドゥーンだったんだ！
Gon's mind is already at its limit!
ところが　長年の連れでさえ みんな「Ｄ」だと思ってやがった！
He's barely holding himself together,
while he waits for Pitou.
したら　ジンの野郎 何て言ったと思う？
I can't let them meet.
((今から　お前は　「Ｄ　Ｗ　Ｕ　Ｎ」で ドゥーンだ))
Even if Palm's heart is still there... It'll have a negative effect now!
電話とパソコンで あっという間に。
Palm!
何が　ひでぇって　あいつは 勘違いで「Ｗ」だけじゃなく
Why are you looking for Gon?
「Ｅ」まで取っちまったんだぞ！ でも　そのおかげで 運気が上がったんでしょ？
Depending on why, I might be
willing to tell you where he is.
まぁな　その日以来　体調は良く…。
Huh? Why are you asking now? There's no reason...
お！
Someone he deeply respects
was completely transformed.
「この中に入れる３枚を決めたら 港へ行ってください」ってさ。
That person had his soul taken away.
いろいろ　おとうさんのことも 聞いたんでしょ？
Right now, Gon is facing off
against the one responsible!
うん　でも今　どこにいるとかは 知らないって。 そっか　やっぱり　ゲームには 手掛かりなしってことかしらね。
If you appear before Gon
looking as you do now...
まっ　最初から　そういう メッセージあったんだもんな。
Gon will...
うん　まぁね。 で　どうするのよさ　選ぶ３枚は。
totally snap.
じゃあ　私は 「ブループラネット」。
So you have to
やっぱり　これだわさ！　あ　早く 現物を拝みたいもんだわさ。
call him by his name first.
うん　考え中 ゴンは決まったか？
You must say, "Gon."
うん　まぁ　一応。 マジ？　どれよ！ えっとね…　これ。
That's the condition.
えっ？ ちょっと何で　それなのよ！
Tell him you're okay.
うん　面白い！ いつから考えてた？ ん　これ見た瞬間からかな。
Before we entered the palace, Gon was really worried about you.
うん　これもいるよね。 えっ？ 大丈夫かな？　これで。 うん。
Give him some peace of mind...
つうか　あれを使うには これしかない。
He was just buying time.
ちょっと　何？　何？ どういうこと？
He had no intention of letting them meet.
ビスケは　いいんだな 「ブループラネット」で。
That was the idea...
ゲームクリア おめでとうございます それでは　あなたのバインダーの 指定ポケットから３枚
make him feel a little better, if you can... Only you can do that now!
選んだのは　ナンバー２ 「一坪の海岸線」
No one else...
８１　「ブループラネット」 ８４　「聖騎士の首飾り」。
can do it.
以上の３枚で 本当によろしいですか？ うん。
I can't...
では　指輪はお返しします お疲れさまでした。
do anything!
ありがとう。 さようなら。
Once he'd said those words, the dam within him burst.
まぁ　あっちも 現実の一部だったしな。
He's completely defenseless.
ちょっと　早く！　早く！ バインダー出してみてよ！
Change in plans... Kill him now, #1!
エヘっ　ゲイン！ キャ！　これよ　これだわさ！ 夢にまで見た　ブループラネット。
When Palm had infiltrated the palace, arriving at the exit Knov had
placed near the stairway, Pitou's En returned.
オホホホ…！　あ　幸せだわさ。 何て呼ぼうかしら　プラちゃん？ プルちゃんかしら？ プラネちゃん？ うん　プラネちゃんが　いいわさ。
Surrounded by aura so evil that she felt
as though she'd be crushed to dust, she reached the same conclusion Knov had.
はっ！　あ…。 で　あんた達はよかったの？ その２枚でさ。
As she watched Pouf slowly and silently
descend the stairs, she made her decision.
ああ　これがベストさ　なっ。 うん。 じゃあ　早速　行くか。 うん！
She plotted to take her own life, so she would look like a despairing girl
who could not bear Bizeff violating her.
ゲイン！
However, Pitou prevented that from happening.
貸して　キルア。
As one cannot help but shiver in the cold, no one could blame Palm for reflexively using aura
よし　出来た！ ＯＫ！
to protect herself from Pitou's evil aura
at the moment she was exposed to it.
なるほどね。 「アカンパニー」を「トランスフォーム」で 指定ポケットカードに変化させ それを「聖騎士の首飾り」で 元に戻す。
The Royal Guard was interested in her aura, and after receiving permission from the fasting King, Pitou and Pouf made her experimental soldier #1.
よく思いついたもんだわさ。
Precedent had demonstrated those who remembered
…にしても　よく実行する気に なったもんだわね。
their pasts had stronger mental fortitude.
指定ポケットカードじゃ　ない 「アカンパニー」を選ぶなんてさ。 うん。 でも最初 俺がゲームに参加する時に
This was most noticeable in Ants who
had learned how to use Nen.
もし　１番じゃなかったら　きっと 確信は持てなかったと思う。 えっ？
Memories of the past tended to both assist
and deter the growth of soldiers.
ここに来る時 ジャンケンしただろ？
Deterrence generally happened
ジャンケン？ ああ。
when memories led to emotional reactions.
スタート地点で キルアを待ってた時 近くには誰もいなかった。
Thus, the two Royal Guards concluded
that they should use Pitou's Dr. Blythe
つまり　俺がゲーム内で 最初に会ったのは
to destroy the connection between
Palm's memories and her emotions.
２番目に入って来た ゴレイヌさんのはず。 けど　自分のバインダー 調べてみたら
The experiments that produced Cheetu
and Leol confirmed that those
その前に１人 会ってる人物がいた。
who retained more of their memories
emerged from their cocoons sooner.
なるほど　ニッグは そのアナグラムってわけね。
To quickly and quietly conquer humanity, leaving soldiers with their memories, while
keeping control of them, would be best.
多分　俺は赤ん坊の頃 ジンと一緒に　ここに来た。
Palm was the perfect test subject.
ジンはきっと 俺に　こう言いたかったんだ。
The success of her experiment would
signify the end of the human race. Now go, #1...
「何を捨てても俺に会いたいなら
Beat the kid before you to death!
このゲームをクリアするくらい 強くなれ」ってね。
Shut up.
大したもんだわさ　その執念。
Palm Siberia.
で　ジンに会ったら まず　何をする？ もちろん　キルアを紹介するよ。
I'm not #1!
バカ！　よせよ！　ハズいだろ！ うぅ…　ホント　やめてよ。
I will never become a pawn to you Ants... Even if it costs my life!
いいえ　遠慮しとくわさ。
Killua...
こぶつきの男に興味ないんでね。
I have you to thank.
そう…。
There was a wall inside my head.
これ以上　一緒にいたら 本当に親の気持になっちゃう
My emotions were separated from my body. I couldn't do anything about it.
それじゃあ　ビスケ　元気でね。
I've been like this since I woke up.
ああ　あんた達もね。
You removed the barrier.
ありがとうございました！ オス！
Don't say that there's nothing you can do.
うん！
If I can do anything to help Gon, I'll be happy to.
「アカンパニー」オン！ ニッグ！
But you must not forget...
この後は Ｇ．Ｉ　ちゅーとりある！
Slow and steady it is.
あっ。 あっ。 この後は Ｇ．Ｉ　ちゅーとりある！ この後は Ｇ．Ｉ　ちゅーとりある！ 父が作ったゲームをクリアし
Soldiers do not need memories or emotions...
ひと回りたくましくなった　ゴン
Which also means I no longer need Pitou's power.
向かった先にいたのは 果たして　ジンなのか？
I can create soldiers on my own!